MARCO MARCHIONNI

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+39 349 877 23 07

marco.marchionni@gmail.com



marcomarchionni.com



via Alfonso Marchesani 56, 66054 Vasto (CH) Italy

SKILLS

Languages

Java, JavaScript, DAX

Frontend

HTML, CSS, SCSS, jQuery, React, React Native, Angular, Bootstrap, Angular Material

Backend

Node.js, Express, Spring, Spring Boot, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools

Git, Maven, Parcel, VSCode, Intellij Idea

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Development Program CareerFoundry

2022-2023

Filmmaking Intensive **New York University**

Laurea cum laude in Lettere Moderne **University of Bologna**

1999

Modern Art and Literature University of Kent, Canterbury

1996

Computer Science University of Bologna

1994

PROFILE

Full-stack developer proficient in a variety of programming languages and frameworks, with the ability to swiftly learn and adapt to new technologies. Strong interpersonal skills and long-term experience in team collaboration and leadership. Developed a unique blend of creativity, technical expertise, and disciplined thinking through key roles in the film and TV industry, as well as in stock and option trading.

LATEST PROJECTS

Portfolio Strategist

Java, Spring Boot, MySql

- · Integrated application with Interactive Brokers web server for user account data
- Developed REST API with Spring Boot for efficient data querying and manipulation.
- Test Driven Development with Mockito and JUnit 5.

Flixit

Backend: Node.js, Express; Frontend: React, Angular

- Connected a MongoDB database with detailed information about Italian movies.
- Constructed a REST API with Node.js and Express to enable user registration and movie information queries.
- Developed two frontend variations (React and Angular) for user login, movie information display, and user-specific favorite movie lists.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Stock and Option Trader

Self-employed

2013-2023

- Conducted long-term investment strategies based on the Motley Fool philosophy.
- Utilized Motley Fool principles for option trading, employing advanced strategies such as bull put/calls, diagonal calls, covered calls, etc.
- Built software tools using Google App Script for data analysis and informed decision making.

TV Producer and Scriptwriter

Mediaset, Rai, Publispei and others

2001-2012, 2019-2021

- Produced multiple popular and award-winning shows for Mediaset, a major Italian TV Network.
- Authored scripts for films and TV series, receiving critical acclaim and recognition.

IT Translator

Zeitgeist, London and others

2014-2019

 Translated IT documentation and marketing material for top-tier international clients including Oracle, MongoDB, Symantec, Digicert, PaloAlto Networks, etc.